What do you read when you are travelling by train or bus?
你坐火车或公交车时读什么？
What are other passengers reading?
其他乘客在读什么？
Perhaps a woman sitting near you is reading a trashy romantic novel.
也许坐在你旁边的一位女士正在读一本俗气的言情小说。
A man is reading a serious biography about a politician.
一位男士正在读关于一个政治家的严肃传记。
And there's a student reading an English textbook.
还有一个学生正在读英语课本。
What do their choices say about them?
他们的选择说明了什么？
Do you judge them by what they are reading?
你会根据他们读的内容来评判他们吗？
I have got to tell you that your impressions of them are probably completely wrong.
我得告诉你，你对他们的印象可能完全错了。
The woman reading the romantic novel could be a lawyer.
读浪漫小说的女士可能是一名律师。
She just wants a light read to take her mind off work.
她只是想读点轻松的东西以便不去想工作的事情。
The man reading the biography wants you to think that he is an intellectual, but he is just showing off.
读传记的男士想让你认为他是个知识分子，但他只是在炫耀。
The student reading the textbook isn't a student at all.
读课本的学生根本不是学生。
She's an English teacher.
她是一名英语老师。
Publishers know that some people are self-conscious about what they read on public transport and so they put out different versions of a cover.
出版商知道有些人对在公共交通工具上读什么感到不自在，因此他们提供了不同版本的封面。
For example, books about Harry Potter have an original cover for young readers and then another more serious version for adults.
例如，关于哈利·波特的书有面向年轻读者的原始封面，还有面向成年人的更严肃的版本。
So next time you are on a train, look around and see what other people are reading, but don't jump to any conclusions.
所以下次你在火车上时，环顾四周看看其他人在读什么，但不要急于下结论。
You will probably be wrong.
你很可能会错。
Here is a situation where you could say, "Don't judge a book by its cover".
这就是一个可以说“不要以貌取人”的情境。